https://www.mpp.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Skip to content
Take Action: Urge your state legislators to support a compassionate medical marijuana program!
Tax DocumentsPress ReleasesIn the Media
PolicyFederal PolicyState PolicyU.S. Territory Policy2020 Ballot InitiativesIssuesCriminal JusticeDecriminalizationEconomicsMarijuana LegalizationLegislationMedical MarijuanaFAQNewsroomPress ReleasesIn the MediaBlogEventsUpdatesPodcastDonateDonate to MPPDonate to MPP FoundationCorporate GivingMembershipShopOther Ways to HelpTake ActionSpread the WordRegister to Vote2020 Gubernatorial Voter Guide2020 State Cannabis Voter Guides
Donate
Menu
About us
Who We Are
MPP TeamBoard of DirectorsJobsContact Us
What We Do
OverviewMission and ValuesOur WorkCampaignsOur History
Resources & Media
Tax DocumentsPress ReleasesIn the Media
PolicyFederal PolicyState PolicyU.S. Territory Policy2020 Ballot InitiativesIssuesCriminal JusticeDecriminalizationEconomicsMarijuana LegalizationLegislationMedical MarijuanaFAQNewsroomPress ReleasesIn the MediaBlogEventsUpdatesPodcastDonateDonate to MPPDonate to MPP FoundationCorporate GivingMembershipShopOther Ways to HelpTake ActionSpread the WordRegister to Vote2020 Gubernatorial Voter Guide2020 State Cannabis Voter Guides
Donate
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Last updated: January 22, 2020
Protecting your privacy is important to the Marijuana Policy Project (MPP). We are committed to keeping your personal information confidential.
Why We Collect Personal Information
Type of Data Collected
When We Disclose Contact Information
How We Protect Your Personal Information
Access to Your Personal Information
Our Organizational Commitment
Cookie / Tracking Technology
Necessary Cookies
1. WHY WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION
MPP collects and uses personal information to provide individuals with news and information regarding MPP. In addition, we use personal information to keep email subscribers up-to-date on the latest marijuana policy news and information we think they’d like to hear about.
2. TYPE OF DATA COLLECTED
MPP may collect the following information for users upon submitting forms on mpp.org:
Name
Email
Phone number
Address
City
State
Browser information
Other information provided by users
3. WHEN WE DISCLOSE CONTACT INFORMATION
Except as provided in this policy, MPP will not share any of your personal information at any time with any organization. MPP will not rent or sell any personal information to a third party. Given that MPP is the largest marijuana policy reform organization in the United States, we may contact you on behalf of another organization doing work related to ours. These updates will be sent by MPP personnel via MPP’s secure system. Your personal information will only be handled by MPP employees who are knowledgeable of all rules and policies regarding securely handling all information. They will protect your personal information in accordance with MPP’s Privacy Policy.
MPP occasionally allows other organizations to send mail to individuals on its lists. In these cases, lists containing only names and addresses (no contribution data or other personal information) are delivered to a third-party mailing house for one-time use for that organization’s mailing. To request that we never allow your contact information to be used even in this secure manner, please contact membership@mpp.org. If possible, please include your full name, postal address, phone number, and the email address at which you receive messages from MPP.
MPP is dedicated to providing a safe and secure environment for your personal information.
4. HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
MPP safeguards the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the internet.
MPP uses industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all webpages where donations are submitted. To make donations to MPP or organizations supported by MPP, you must use an SSL-enabled browser. (Any current version of Firefox, Chrome, Internet Explorer, or Safari will work.) This protects the confidentiality of your personal and credit card information while it is transmitted over the internet.
5. ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
If you would like your personal information updated, modified, or removed, you can contact membership@mpp.org with your request. If possible, please include your full name, postal address, phone number, and the email address at which you receive messages from MPP.
Privacy Tools
Third-Party Vendors
NeonCRM is a third-party data processor which handles data, including personally identifiable information. You can update subscriptions and your profile information with their account manager.
6. OUR ORGANIZATIONAL COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY
MPP does not knowingly solicit personal information from children or send them requests for personal information.
MPP will not rent or sell any personal information to a third party. MPP’s website contains limited links to other sites. MPP does not share your personal information with those sites, nor is MPP responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of those organizations.
If we are going to use your personal information differently from what is stated here, we will try to contact you via email using the most recent information we have. If you have not given us permission to communicate with you, you will not be contacted, nor will we use your personal information in a new manner.
7. COOKIE/TRACKING TECHNOLOGY
This site uses cookie and tracking technology. The cookies are useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the site, and understanding how visitors use the site. If you have enabled the Do Not Track feature of your browser on Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, or Chrome, the site’s cookie tracking technology will be disabled.
Necessary Cookies
Category
Cookie
Description
Expiration
CloudFlareCloudflare, Inc. is a U.S. company that provides content delivery network services, DDoS mitigation, Internet security and distributed domain name server services, sitting between the visitor and the Cloudflare user's hosting provider, acting as a reverse proxy for websites.
__cfduid
This cookie is used to identify individual clients behind a shared IP address and apply security settings on a per-client basis.
1 yr
Performance Cookies
Category
Cookie
Description
Expiration
Google AnalyticsGoogle Analytics lets us measure site performance by tracking visits and page views.
__ga
Used to distinguish users.
2 yrs
__gid
Used to distinguish users.
24 hrs
__utma
Used to distinguish users and sessions. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utma cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.
2 yrs
__utmc
Not used in ga.js. Set for interoperability with urchin.js. Historically, this cookie operated in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether the user was in a new session/visit.
End of browser session
__utmz
Stores the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached your site. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.
6 mos
__utmt
Used to throttle request rate.
10 mins
__utmb
Used to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utmb cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.
30 mins
8. COLLECTION OF INFORMATION
MPP collects personally identifiable information, like names, postal addresses, email addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by our visitors. The information you provide is used to fulfill your specific request. Personal information submitted when donating to MPP, MPP Foundation, the MPP PAC, or subscribing to MPP email alerts will not be shared with other groups, but MPP may occasionally allow like-minded organizations to send mailings to you, whereby MPP doesn’t actually share your contact info with these like-minded organizations.
We use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements when you visit our website. These companies may use aggregated (not personal identifying) information about your visits to this website in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. These companies may also use cookies on our site for advertising purposes on our and other sites.
9. THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING COOKIES OPT-OUT
We are dedicated to providing privacy on the internet. In addition to developing our privacy policy, we have provided you the opportunity to opt out of future third-party advertising cookies.
These terms do not cover the collection methods or use of the information collected by these vendors. These vendors have their own privacy policies and may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”).  To remove yourself from some or all NAI member advertising programs, please visit the NAI Opt-Out Page and follow the relevant instructions.  Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.
10. CREDIT CARD INFORMATION
Credit card numbers are not stored by us. They are submitted directly to a secure third-party vendor for processing.
11. COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY
Your personally identifiable information is kept secure. Only authorized employees and vendors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All emails and newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further mailings.
12. THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS
Portions of the mpp.org site (donation processing, the MPP store, and action center) are operated by third-party service providers, which are currently NeonCRM, Shopify, and One Click Politics, respectively. These providers may place cookies on your computer in order to store information, such as items placed in your shopping cart in the MPP store or storing your account login when using the One Click Politics action center. These providers may log standard technical information, such as the numerical internet protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the browser software you use and your operating system; the date and time you access our site; and the internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site.
These providers may also store and organize the personal information collected through their site functions on MPP's behalf.
From time to time, MPP may work with third-party consultants or other service providers who have access to personally identifiable information. In such cases, we will restrict their use of personally identifiable information in accordance with their assigned tasks and subject to the limitations of this privacy policy.
Get Email Alerts
Signup
Sign up to receive the monthly MPP Insider newsletter and periodic updates regarding marijuana policy issues
Legal cannabis sales begin in Maine! ...
Oct 09, 2020
Vermont Gov. Scott will not veto bill to legalize and regulate cannabis sales! ...
Oct 07, 2020
Va. lawmakers send cannabis reforms to governor’s desk! ...
Oct 05, 2020
S.C.: Medical cannabis voter guide published as absentee voting begins ...
Oct 05, 2020
Vermont bill to legalize and regulate sales arrives on governor’s desk ...
Marijuana Policy Project 1995 - 2020. All right reserved. | Privacy Policy
